

Associate seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering (c#, Asp.net, Ado. Net, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, Database).



Current Designation: Senior Consultant Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt Ltd Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Chennai Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Coimbatore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Associate, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project

Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement

Gathering,c#,JavaScript,Oracle,jQuery,ASP.Net,ADO.Net,HTML,CSS,SVN

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

6.4 years of experience in software development and maintenance using Microsoft .Net technology.

SYNOPSIS Currently serving Cognizant, India as Associate (Dot net Developer).

Technical expertise in Software Development Life Cycle entailing requirement analysis, design,

development, testing, troubleshooting & implementation.

Demonstrated excellence in successfully completing the requirements.

An effective communicator with excellent analytical skills and ability to relate to people at any level

of business and management.

Eager to learn new technologies in recent trend

Work Experience

Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt Ltd as Senior Consultant

Sep 2020 to Till Date

Cognizant as Associate May 2014 to Aug 2020

Title: Windshield Role: Dotnet developer Period: Nov 2014 - Aug 2020 Client: Walgreens pharmacy, USA

Key Technologies: C#, ASP.NET, JavaScript, jQuery, Oracle.

Tools: Visual studio 2017, Oracle SQL developer

Web based Application developed for submitting and tracking issues across all the specialty pharmacy

sites. And mostly used by Information Technology

Operations

In information technology any new projects or new enhancements or bug fixing for existing applications are tracked using this application. In operations it is used to log and track the crediting and regulatory issues.

The issues are logged by the users when they are found or reported by a customer and tracked using

this application.

The major purpose of this applications is not just issue tracking, it also has an ability to provide the data required to generate a report by which we can identify and rectify the drawbacks for a better and quality business.

Application major enhancement happens whenever new business is acquired or altered and then application will be enhanced based on the requirement.

Application also includes Advanced search, Mail reports, Quick submit, schedulers, batch process, services and admin role functionalities.

Roles and Responsibilities in the Project

Developer

Client Facing role

Involved in the requirement analysis of new enhancements.

Involved in Design, Development, Code review and Unit Testing.

Involved in creating stored procedures, functions & views

Developed code in adherence to the existing coding standards

Responsible for solving the problems, bug fixing, troubleshooting in application.

Participated in hackathon events and won awards twice for ideas & customer appreciation.

Handled client in the requirement, development & deployment phases for 6 years.

Implemented innovative ideas specific to application to reduce time and efforts

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from Prathyusa Institute of Technology and Management, Chennai in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
C#	
ASP.NET	
ADO.NET	
Oracle	
SQL	
HTML	
JavaScript	
JQUERY	
CSS	
.NET	
MS Test (Unit Testing)	
IIS	
OOPS	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=22507da194ccedabeea689e552b2e4c20d0f080449450a435517405d5c...

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time